# LEE, JEONGHOON

T. 514-992-1279 hoon22.lee@gmail.com

https://jeonghoon-lee.github.io/resume/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeonghoon-lee-996a3483/

# **Qualifications Summary**

Looking for a junior software developer position, ideally in backed, with Java, JavaScript, C#, PHP and C++ programming skills and good knowledge of databases. Abilities in the analysis, development, debugging and testing. Extensive experience in developing software applications over 10 years in South Korea. I would really like to start a new career as a developer in Canada.

# **Relevant Skills and Tools**

- Java, Java Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Security, JPA, Hibernate
- JavaScript, Node.js, React, React Hooks, Redux, AJAX, JSON, Express, NPM
- Dotnet C#, WPF, Entity Framework
- Databases: MS SQL Server, MySQL Server, Oracle, Google Firebase, Mongo DB, MeekroDB
- Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA, NetBeans, Eclipse, Visual Studio
- Agile Methodology, Scrums, Kanban Tools

# **Other Skills and Tools**

- HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Bootstrap
- PHP, Fat-Free for PHP Framework, Visual C++, C, Delphi, Android App development
- Multi-thread and Network programming, Mpeg-2/H.264 Encoding/Decoding/Transmitting Programming

### **Education**

- AEC Program of Web and Database Programming, Vanier College, Jan. 2021 ~ May 2021
- AEC Program of Internet Programming and Development, John Abbott College, Oct. 2018 ~ Aug. 2020
- Master of Computer Science\*, <u>Kyungpook National University</u> (South Korea), 1995 ~ 1997
- Bachelor of Computer Science\*, Kyungpook National University (South Korea), 1991 ~ 1995
  - \* Canadian equivalency credential was evaluated by WES (World Education Service)

## Languages

• English: High Intermediate, French: Pre-Intermediate, Korean: Native

# **Professional Experience**

#### **Electromechanical Assembler**

June 2014 ~ June 2018

Micanan Systems

Dorval, Quebec, Canada

- Read and understand technical drawings, specifications, schematics, and diagrams.
- Assembly, install, and test using instruments.

## Freelance Software Developer

Aug 2010 ~ Dec 2013

Seoul, South Korea

- Develop a system monitoring software to monitor, control and maintain remote devices.
- Design, develop and maintain a software application in the factory automation industry such as an automated camera module testing equipment for LG Electronics. and an automated packaging equipment for Samsung Electronics.
- Visual C++, Win32, MFC, Visual Basic, Delphi, MS SQL Server, Machine vision library
- TCP/IP, UDP/IP, Serial Communication (RS232, RS422, RS485), SNMP, DeviceNet

## Senior Developer / Software team

May 2006 ~ Aug 2009

Acetel Co. Ltd.

Seoul, South Korea

- Assign, coordinate, and review team members' works and activities.
- Design, programming, test, and debug software product
- Project leader of H.264 professional IRD (Integrated Receiver/Decoder) system development and develop remote control software to monitor and manage the IRDs with SNMP protocol
- Visual C++, WIN32, MFC, Linux, Multicasting and MS SQL Server

### Senior Researcher Engineer / R&D department

May 2000 ~ Apr 2006

Gunjarm Digital Co. Ltd.

Seoul, South Korea

- Develop, maintain, and support Audio/Video encoding, decoding, and transmitting systems for high quality video surveillance.
- Design and develop SDKs of the PCI-type encoding boards in Windows environment.
- Visual C++, WIN32, MFC, Embedded XP, UDP/IP, RTP/RTSP, Multicast Networking

## Junior Researcher Engineer / R&D department

Feb 1997 ~ Apr 2000

Nongshim Data System (NDS) Co. Ltd.

Seoul, South Korea

- Design, develop and maintain web mailing system and knowledge management system using CGI, Java, and JavaScript in HP-UX Environment.
- Develop and maintain an electronic mailing and approval system using MS Exchange Server